

# Yuva Prashanth

An exuberant entrepreneur with a profound aptitude for technology, crafting groundbreaking applications. Fuelled by a relentless curiosity, I thrive on unearthing novel advancements. Currently, I seek an opportunity to channel my expertise towards organizational growth, actively participating in technological evolution, and embracing resourcefulness, innovation, and adaptability.

vuvaprashanth20@gmail.com



8309048387



💡 5-3-237,Vijaya Lakshmi Street, Tirupati, India

#### **EDUCATION**

## B.Tech - Computer Science Engineering Annamacharya Institution of Technology and

07/2018 - 08/2022

Tirupati, India

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Full Stack MERN Developer **SALESFORCE**

07/2022 - 04/2023

Bangalore, India

Designed web applications

- Innovated industry-leading tools to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of our client-centric assignments, resulting in a 40% increase in code usability and a 80% reduction in code defects.
- Performed code reviews and successfully delivered over 20 highly responsive solutions in 5 software design projects with user experience.

## Co - Founder **PACENAV**

09/2021 - 05/2022

Bangalore, India

Web Application for Indoor Navigation with GPS

- Led network services startup strategy that directly resulted in 4x speed in navigation. Conducted evaluative testing with 10+ participants and Successfully led design, negotiation.
- Collaborated with 5 developers and 3 design members to prioritize coding results in RESTful services.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

District Winners in Sports (Cricket)

Finalist in year 2019

Best Mobile App Design in Technical Fest

Conducted in Annamacharya Institute Of Technology and Sciences

Non-Technical Event Winners in "The state of Art and Recreational Event"

It is conducted in the view of exhibiting the student extra curricular activity

#### **SKILLS**



#### **PROJECT**

Voxify (12/2021 - 02/2022)

- Optimized performance and security by 30% with 2-way unit testing. Utilized cloud computing for reliable deployment.
- Improved user experience by 40% and project scope by 15% using react voice recognition development library.

NutriSearch (02/2020 - 02/2020)

- Reduced 30% latency and boosted 15% scalability with Webpack, State Management libraries, and react frameworks
- Integrated Edamam API for search engine, delivering highly responsive design and server-side performance with a 2x improvement

WriteNow (08/2019 - 11/2019)

- Strengthened user trust by 25% with 2-factor JWT authentication authorization and continuous integration development.
- Streamlined code quality standards using industry-leading react tools that clean defects by 50% and boost code usability by 30%.

## REFERENCE

Dr. S Sunil Kumar, Ph.D

Head Of Placement Management, Computer Science Department, Phone No:9652775362, Email: sunilkumar4@gmail.com